emediate.biz 2017-06-10

# OUR PRIVACY POLICY | cxense

Cxense ASA (“Cxense”) provides web-based services to other businesses (“Clients”) to improve the overall relevance of their web applications. These services are advertising, analytics, search and personalization. Cxense and its Clients are commonly referred to below as “we” or “us”.

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you about how Cxense technology collects information, and how this information is processed by our services to give you a better overall web experience. This Privacy Policy applies to all of the products, services, and websites operated by or enabled by Cxense, our subsidiaries, or affiliated companies. From time to time, we may also post product- or service-specific privacy notices or documentation to explain in more detail how Cxense products and services handle information related to privacy.

The US Federal Government and participants in the technology industry have developed some practical guidelines to help you guard against Internet fraud, secure your computer, and protect your personal information. Cxense supports your use and implementation of these guidelines

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact Cxense at [privacy@cxense.com](https://mail.google.com/mail/?view=cm&fs=1&tf=1&to=privacy@cxense.com) or write to us at;

 **Cxense ASA**  
Attn.: Privacy Advocate  
P.O. Box 2920 Solli  
NO-0230 Oslo  
Norway

## INFORMATION WE COLLECT AND HOW WE USE IT:

### Cookies

When you visit Cxense, or a website powered by Cxense technology, one or more cookies is sent to your computer, or handheld device. These cookies are used to help improve the quality of our service, including for storing user preferences, improving ad selection, content recommendations, and search results, as well as tracking user trends, such as what content people consume. We also use cookies in our advertising services to help advertisers and publishers serve and manage ads across the web.

### Log information

When you access our services via a browser, application or other client, Cxense servers automatically record certain information. These server logs may include information such as your web request, your interaction with a service, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser or your account.

### Affiliated Cxense services on Client sites

Cxense offers most services on or through its Client’s websites or applications. Information that you provide to those sites may be sent to Cxense to deliver the service. We process such information under this Privacy Policy.

### Location data

We may offer location-enabled services, such as local search and location-based advertising. If you use those services, we may receive information about your actual location (such as GPS signals sent by a mobile device) or information that can be used to approximate a location (such as a cell ID or IP address).

### Client sites

This Privacy Policy applies only to services enabled by Cxense. We do not exercise control over Client websites, sites that include Cxense applications, products or services, or links from within our various services under the control of Clients. Clients may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data, or solicit personal information from you.

In addition to the above, we may use the information we collect using Cxense technology to provide, maintain, protect, improve our services (including advertising services), develop new services; and protect the rights or property of Cxense or its Clients.

Cxense processes information on servers in the United States of America and in other countries. In some cases, information collected by Cxense is also processed outside your own country.

### Your choice to opt out

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some Cxense features and services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.

You can choose to opt out from Cxense personalization and ad targeting by going to our preferences page, and click on the “Opt Out” button. When you opt out, an opt-out cookie will be placed on your computer. The opt-out cookie tells Cxense not to collect your information to tailor online advertisement campaigns, or enable other personalized services. Please note that if you delete, block, or otherwise restrict cookies, or if you use a different computer or Internet browser, you may need to renew your opt-out choice.

### Information security

Cxense always make its best efforts in providing security measures to protect against unauthorized access to or unauthorized alteration, disclosure, or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of data collection, storage, and processing practices and security measures, including appropriate encryption and physical security measures to guard against unauthorized access to systems where Cxense stores data.

### Enforcement

Cxense is headquartered in Oslo, Norway, and also operates in many other legal jurisdictions. While Cxense will always do its best to adhere to the principles and policies in the country you live in, sometimes this is not possible. Cxense is required to conform with the European Union’s Data Protection Directive (Directive 95/46/EC, which is also embodied in the US Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of Notice, Choice, Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity, Access and Enforcement, and Safe Harbor Policies).

Cxense regularly reviews its compliance in view of this Directive. If formal written complaints is received, it is Cxense’s policy to in a timely fashion contact the complaining user regarding his or her concerns. Cxense will cooperate with the appropriate regulatory authorities, including local data protection authorities, to resolve any complaints regarding the transfer of data that cannot be resolved between Cxense and an individual. Cxense compliance and ongoing certifications with regards to Safe Harbor Privacy Principles will be posted on the Cxense website.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. Cxense will post any Privacy Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, a more prominent notice will be provided.
